Guide to the William Lockhart Clayton papers, 1897-1998 MS 007
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series VI: Personal and Family Correspondence, 1899-1964; 250197; 5 boxes, 2.5 linear ft.
  - Subseries B: Photocopied correspondence from repositories other then Rice, 250198
    - Personal family correspondence (photocopies), 1923; 250205 (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Personal family correspondence (photocopies), 1924-26; 250204 (Box 95, Folder 9)
    - Personal family correspondence (photocopies), 1927-28; 250203 (Box 95, Folder 10)
    - Personal family correspondence (photocopies), 1929-30; 250202 (Box 95, Folder 11)
    - Personal family correspondence (photocopies), 1931-32; 250201 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Personal family correspondence (photocopies), n.d. (ca. 1920-40); 250200 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Personal correspondence (photocopies) to Ellen Garwood from parents, 1940-57.; 250199 (Box 96, Folder 3)
- Series VII: Personal Financial Records, 1897-1956, 250194; 2 folders, 0.25 linear inches
  - WLC business, personal, and financial correspondence and records (original and photocopy), 1897-1958; 250196 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Financial records re renovation of Clayton's Southmore residence, 1917; 250195 (Box 96, Folder 5)
- Series VIII: Biographical Material, 1927-1998, 250188; 2 boxes, 1.0 linear ft.
  Includes one transcript of an interview with Clayton, and two works about Clayton.
  - "The Reminiscences of William Lockhart Clayton", Oral History Research Office, Columbia University, 239 pg. transcript of interview with Clayton, New York City, 1962; 250193 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Typescript of Gregory Fossedal's WLC biography published in 1993 as "Our Finest Hour," folder 1 of 3, (March 1991; 250192 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Typescript of Gregory Fossedal's WLC biography published in 1993 as "Our Finest Hour," folder 2 of 3, (March 1991; 250191 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Typescript of Gregory Fossedal's WLC biography published in 1993 as Our Finest Hour, folder 3 of 3, (March 1991; 250190 (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Ross Joseph Pritchard thesis, "Will Clayton: A Study of Business Statesmanship", 1955; 250189 (Box 97, Folder -)
- Series IX: Ellen Garwood, 1947-1977, 250167; 1 Linear Feet
  Correspondence and oral history interviews created or acquired by Will Clayton's daughter's, Ellen Garwood, in researching her father's history.
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, 1951-77; 250184
    - Correspondence (original and photocopy) to and from Ellen Garwood (incls. Atlantic Union, Clayton Center, recollections of WLC), 1951-77; 250187 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (photocopy) from Helen Ainsworth (WLC secretary) to Ellen Garwood, 1956-58; 250186 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence (photocopy) from Clair Wilcox to Ellen Garwood, 58; 250185 (Box 98, Folder 2a)
  - Subseries B: Transcripts (photocopies) of Ellen Garwood's interviews, 1958-59; 250172
    - Anderson, Dean, 1958; 250183 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Brown, Winthrop, 1956; 250182 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Collado, Emilio G., 1958; 250181 (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - Hawkins, Harry, 1959; 250180 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Merchant, Livingston, and Douglas, Lewis, 1958; 250179 (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - Ness, Norman, 1958-59; 250178 (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - Nitze, Paul, 250177 (Box 98, Folder 9)
    - Stevens, Arthur, 1958; 250176 (Box 98, Folder 10)
    - Stillwell, James, 1958; 250175 (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - Stinebower, LeRoy, 1958; 250174 (Box 98, Folder 12)
    - White, Ivan, 1958; 250173 (Box 98, Folder 13)
  - Ellen Garwood notes from State Department files, 250171 (Box 98, Folder 14-17)
  - Correspondence between State Dept. and Ellen Garwood, 1958-65; 250170 (Box 98, Folder 18)
  - Notes of Ellen Garwood, 1947; 250169 (Box 98, Folder 19)
  - Notes of W.L. Garwood, 250168 (Box 98, Folder 20)
- Series X: Family and WLC Memorabilia and History, 1899-1998; 250154
  This series includes family photographs, newsclippings, announcements, transcription of Burdine Clayton's diary, Will Clayton's passports, and a history of the Johnson and Clayton families.
  - Family photographs and negatives. Subjects include Will Clayton, Burdine Clayton, James (Clayton?), Anderson Family, and other unidentified persons and homes., 1926, n.d.; 250166 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Family newsclippings,. certificates and announcements (photocopies), relating to births, deaths, and marriages., ca. 1899-1902; 250165 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Will Clayton passports (1914, 1927, 1929, 1935, 1939, 1948, 1954, 1958) and Susan Clayton passport (1947), 250164 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Documents regarding Will Clayton's health and legal status, 1936-37; 250163 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Will Clayton's notes on his South American trip, 1937; 250162 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Will Clayton's schedule of speeches and staements, 1950-64; undated text of one speech endorsing Mrs. C.A. Chase, Candidate for City Commissioner, Pos. No. 4, 250161 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Condolence letters to Will Clayton on the death of his father, S.M. Clayton, 1926; 250160 (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - "A Line a Day" diary of Burdine Clayton, at the National Cathedral School, Washington, DC, 1927: transcription by Burdine Clayton Johnson, 1996, 250159 (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - "Johnson and Clayton Family History," compiled by Burdine Clayton Johnson, 1998 (photocopy), 250158 (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Maps of Bretton Woods, NH; small unidentified notebook and list, 250157 (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - Leather pouch which formerly contained 16mm film of U.N. conference with U.S. delegates, n.d. (film deteriorated via vinegar syndrome beyond repair and was discarded by WRC, 2003), 250156 (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - Card file boxes (index), 250155 (Box 100-102)
- Series XI: Oversized Materials, 250150
  - Photos, drawings of WLC, 250153 (Drawer 33)
  - Certificates of appointment (Ass't Secretary of State, Under Secretary of State for Economic Affairs, U.S. Alternate Governor of International Monetary Fund and of International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, and Deputy Member to Conference of Food and Agricultural Organization of U.N.), 250152 (Drawer 33)
  - Certificate of appreciation for assistance in American Program for the Brussels Exhibition, 1958; 250151 (Drawer 33)